Henry Escobar

Seattle, WA | 360-842-6406 | henrye@gmail.com <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>GitHub</u> | <u>Blog</u> | <u>Website</u>

FULLSTACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

I create products and services with practical uses to enhance people's lives. I'm driven by 10+ years of experience in the fast paced creative and health fields to collaborate with others in finding adaptable, maintainable solutions that resonate with an individual's evolving needs.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Javascript (ES6), React, Ruby, Rails, HTML, CSS, Git, ActiveRecord

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Gym Bunny - Github | Demo

Intensify your workouts with expertly crafted exercise routines made for you.

- Implemented image uploads by using Rail's Active Storage.
- Persisted user sessions between browser refresh with the use of cookies.
- Authenticated users with the bcrypt engine for secure account creation and login.

Treasured Trails - Github | Demo

Find your next adventure by exploring the experiences of other fellow hikers alike.

- Facilitated the use of props through React's useContext hook.
- Validated the state of objects from user input with a variety of Active Record validation methods.
- Developed Javascript/React frontend to effectively work with Rails/Postgres backend.

Vamonos - Github | Demo

A travel companion to catalog all your upcoming destinations.

- Applied styling techniques leveraging CSS design patterns to improve the user experience.
- Improved loading times by limiting the number of SQL gueries using associated records.
- Created custom and nested routes using React Router to avoid unnecessary page rendering.

EXPERIENCE

PhotographerFreelance
Seattle, WA
2015 - Present

- Photographed high-quality images for various print and digital projects.
- Edited, toned, captioned, and uploaded photographs for publication.
- Built upon client ideas and visions to achieve desired results.
- Collaborated with other photographers and videographers to capture special events.
- Managed and organized photo catalog using consistent naming conventions and key-wording for search optimization.

Customer Experience Supervisor

Banana Republic

San Francisco, CA 04/2013 - 11/2014

- Drove resolutions of customer inquiries by using techniques aligned with company's mission.
- Trained new hires to achieve hourly sales goals and acquire customer loyalty.
- Implemented daily operating procedures to keep the store adequately stocked.

EDUCATION

Flatiron SchoolSeattle, WA

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript programming

05/2022 - 07/2023